FAHID MOHAMMED

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER & PHD RESEARCHER (RESEARCH: TRANSPARENCY IN MULTI-AGENT SYSTEMS(AI))

I am a full-stack software developer currently rounding up a PhD in computer science. I have worked on several apps published on the app-store amongst which is my pet-project "emergency" that was national nominee for the mGovernemnt and participation category of the world summit awards in 2014. More recently I have pivoted to AI and developing LLM based applications.

EXPERIENCE

ENGINEER, HAEMA.CO; REMOTE - 2023-2024

As part of the founding team, I explored the use of AI in the day to day management of diabetes. Given it was a startup environment (pre-funding), we each wore several hats. Amongst my responsibilities were to: Develop an AI agent using LangChain to work with diabetics (this involved using RAG and Pinecone vector DB), Design APIs to integrate the AI with mobile client, Identify potential areas of misuse of the AI and corresponding guardrails to ensure safe use. Review data required for the AI's operation and their relevance to GPDR and HIPAA compliance. Develop and release an iOS app that integrated with Apple HealthKit, StoreKit and other framework and consumed the AI APIs previously mentioned. Set-up and lead the public beta testing programme through TestFlight. Develop a widget for the app using WidgetKit.

AI DEVELOPER & DESIGNER, YOKERU; REMOTE, UK - 2023-2024

As part of a team focused on using Al-based technologies to assist the elderly, my responsibilities included: Full-stack software development (implementing new systems and maintaining existing ones), Identifying ways to improve system reliability and working with stakeholders to implement them. Providing B2B customer support and liaising with businesses to understand how they use the platform and what how best it can be tailored to support their workflows.

CASUAL SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, SYNKD; REMOTE, UK - 2022-2023 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, EHEALTH; NG - 2017-2018 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, ECNX; UK - 2016-2017

In these roles, I worked as a full-stack software developer in an agile team that was either co-located or remote. I was responsible for implementing mockups developed by UI/X team members, designing and implementing APIs and various backend functionalities, reviewing code submitted, training interns. Have a look at one of the previous projects I worked on here: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.lomis&pcampaignid=web_share

The above summaries do not paint a picture of the technologies I've used for development though these have listed in the skills section below. In addition to these roles I have worked as a teaching assistant (tutor or instructor) at several institutions including: University of Bath, JAIN Online, Capita, Code first girls, Skills union. As a teaching assistant, I have taught full-stack software development (MERN Stack), Python (for Al development, data analysis and data visualisation(using Dash)), C, Java, Software Engineering, Intelligent Agents and Intelligent Control & Cognitive Systems to name a few. In all the institutions I have taught at, I have a hight rating which can be shared upon request. My linked in has a list of some projects I have worked on though it does not contain my freelancing portfolio.

My LinkedIn profile contains the full list of organisations I have worked for

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF BATH, UK - PHD COMPUTER SCIENCE, [AWAITING OUTCOME] UNIVERSITY OF BATH, UK - MSC SOFTWARE SYSTEMS, 2015 (MERIT)

SKILLS

Databases / Db Infrastructure: CouchDB, Firebase, MongoBB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, PouchDB, SQLite, Supabase.

Frameworks: AngularJS, Bubble.io, Dash, Django, Electron, ExpressJS / NodeJS, iOS Development with SwiftUI, LangChain, React, ReactNative.

Languages: C, C#, GraphQL, HTML, Java, JavaScript, Python, Swift, SQL, TypeScript, VB.NET.

Tech Stack: APIs, Agile Development (Kanban, Scrum), AWS (also Digital Ocean, Heroku & Modal), CI/CD (TravisCI, Xcode Cloud), Docker, Git / GitHub, Jira, Kubernetes, LangChain, Pinecone, TestFlight.